in the future self-driving cars will be safer and more reliable than humans
but for this to happen we need technologies that allow cars to respond faster than humans
we need
algorithms that can drive
better than humans
and we need cameras that can see more
then humans can see
for example
imagine a self-driving car is about to make a blind turn
and there's an oncoming car or perhaps there's a child about to run into the street
fortunately are
future car will have the superpower
a camera that can see around corners to detect these potential hazards
for the past few years as a PhD student in the Stanford computational Imaging lab
I've been working on a camera that can do just this
a camera that can image objects
Kiddin Around corners or blocked from direct line of sight
so let me give you an example of what our camera can see
this is an outdoor with experiment we conducted where our camera system is scanning the side of this building with the laser
and the scene that we want to capture
is hidden around the corner behind this curtain
so a camera system can't actually see it directly
and yet somehow
are camera can still capture
the 3D geometry
of the scene
so how do we do this
the match
happens here in this camera system
you can think of this as a type of high speed camera
not one that operates at 1000 frames per second
or
even a million frames per second
a trillion frames per second
so fast
Vatican actually capture the movement
of life itself
and to give you an example of just
how fast light travels
what's compared to the speed
have a fast running comic book superhero
who can move it up to three times the speed of sound
it takes a pulse of life
about 3.3 billionths of a second
or 3.3 nanoseconds
the travel the distance of a meter
in that same time
our superhero has move
less than the width of a human hair
that's pretty fast
actually we need to image much faster if you want to capture light moving at subcentimeter Scales
door camera system can capture photons
at time frames of
50 trillionth of a second
450 picosecond
can we take this
Ultra high-speed camera
and we pair it with the laser that sends out short pulses of light
each pulse travels to this visible wall and some light scatters back door camera
we also use the wall to scatter light around the corner to the hidden
we repeat this measurement many times
the capture the arrival times of many photons from different locations on the wall
and after we capture this measurement
we can create a trillion frames per second video of the wall
well this world may look ordinary to our own eyes
at a trillion frames per second
we can see something truly incredible
we can actually see
waves of light
scattered back from the hidden scene
splashing against the wall
each of these waves carries information about the hidden object that sent it
so we can take these measurements
and passed them into a reconstruction algorithm
do then recover the 3D geometry
of this hidden scene
now I want to show you one more example
of an indoor scene that we capture
this time with a variety of different hidden objects
Elizabeth have different appearances
so they reflect light differently
for example the glossy dragon statue reflects light differently than the mirror disco ball
or
the white discus thrower statue
do we can actually see the differences in the reflected light
by visualizing it as this
3D Volume
where we
just taking the video frames and stack them together
end time here is represented as the depth dimension of this Cube
is bright dots that you see our reflections of light from each of the mirrored facets of the disco ball scattering against the wall over time
the bright streaks of light that you see arriving soonest in time
are from the glossy dragon statue that's closest to the wall
and the other streaks of light come from
reflections of light from the bookcase and from the statue
no we can also visualize these measurements
a frame by frame as a video
to directly see the scattered light
and again here we see first
reflections of light from the dragon closest to the wall
followed by
right.
from the disco ball
another Reflections from the bookcase
and finally we see
the reflected waves of light
from the statue
these waves of light
Illuminating the wall
Arlo
fireworks
that lasts for just
trillionth of a second
and even though these objects reflect light
differently
we can still
reconstruct their shapes
and this is what you can see from around the corner
I want to show you one more example that's slightly
in this video you see me dressed in this reflective suit
and our camera system is scanning the wall at a rate of 4 times every second
suit is reflective so we can actually capture enough photons
that we can see
where I am and what I'm doing
without the camera actually directly
Imaging
by capturing photons that scatter from the wall
to my tracksuit
back to the wall and back to the camera
we can capture this
indirect video
in real time
and we think that this type of
practical non-line-of-sight Imaging
could be useful for application
including for self-driving cars
but also for
biomedical Imaging where we need to see into the
tiny structures of the body
perhaps we could also put similar camera systems on the robots that we send to explore other planets
they may have heard about see around corners before but
what I showed you today would have been impossible just two years ago
for example we can now image large room size hidden scenes
outdoors and a real-time rates
and we made
significant advancements worth making this a practical technology
they could actually see on a car Sunday
of course they're still challenges remaining
app for example
can we image
hidden scenes at long distances
there were plenty very very few photons
with lasers that are low power and that are I say
can we create images from Photon set of scattered around many more times
play just a single bounce around the corner
can we take our prototype system
well currently large and bulky
and miniaturize it into something that could be useful for biomedical Imaging
perhaps thesaurus
improved home security system
or can we take this
new Imaging modality
and use it for other applications I think it's an exciting new technology
and there could be other things that
we haven't thought of yet
fusiform
and so
well a future with self-driving cars may seem distant to us now
we're already developing the technologies that could make cars safer and more intelligent
and with the rapid pace of
scientific discovery and innovation
you never know what new and exciting capabilities
could be just around the corner